Those
namaskar
video
questions.
Overall,
important questions,
English version.
video
question.
First question is which among the
following is the regulator for the
insurance industry in India. Friends, uh
as all of you know that IRDI is the
regulator for all the insurance company
whether it is general insurance, life
insurance and health insurance. For all
the insurance company, IRDI is the
regulatory.
So the answer is insurance regulatory
and development authority of India.
Next, which among the following is a
method of risk transfer? Friends, I have
already told you about the risk
transfer. Risk transfer means insurance.
So the answer is
insurance.
Next question is which of the below
insurance scheme is run by an unsoler
and not as sponsored by the government.
Uh when we see the options the first two
options employee state insurance
corporation and crop insurance scheme
these two scheme are run by the
government. So the answer is Jan arrog.
Next risk transfer through risk pooling
is called dash. Friends I have already
told you risk transfer means insurance.
So the correct answer is
insurance.
Next. The measures to reduce chances of
occurrence of risk is known as dash.
The correct answer is loss prevention.
Suppose you have a shop or office and
there is a possibility of fire in shop
or office then what can we do? We can
install fire extinguisher and in case of
any fire.
It help us to reduce the losses. So
installing a fire extinguisher is a
measure to reduce chances of occurrence
of risk.
Next is by transferring risk to insurer
it become possible dash.
Let's say you have a shop and a stock of
rupees 10 lakh in that shop. If it get
stolen or set on fire, what will happen?
You suffered loss. So what can you do?
If you get your SOP insured then
whatever the loss incurred it will
compensated by the insurance company. So
you need not to worries about the risk
like theft or fire in your shop and you
can do your work peacefully and can make
plan for improving your business.
So the correct answer is D to enjoy
peace of mind and plan one's business
more effectively.
Next question is origins of modern
insurance business can be traced to
dash.
The correct answer is Lloyds.
All of you know insurance business was
started from Lloyds.
Next is in insurance context risk
retention indicate a situation where
dash
we have already learned about risk
retention and risk transfer. Risk
transfer means insurance buying
insurance and risk retention means not
buying a insurance. So if a person who
is not buying a insurance that means he
decide to bear the risk and it effects.
So the correct answer is D. One decides
to bearer the risk and its effects.
Identify the scenario where a debate on
the need of insurance is not required.
The correct answer is motor insurance
for third party liability. Friends, all
of you know that motor insurance,
vehicle insurance is compulsory
and if you don't want to buy the
comprehensive insurance for your bike
but this is compulsory that you have to
buy the third party liability insurance.
Next question is in India dash insurance
is mandatory.
This question is also related with the
previous question. So the answer is
motor third party liability which is
compulsory and which is mandatory to
buy.
Why do insurers arrange for survey and
inspection of the property before
acceptance of a risk?
The correct answer is to assess the risk
for rating purpose.
Next question is which of the below
party is not eligible to enter into a
life insurance contract.
Friends, all of you know that insurance
contract is a legal contract and to sign
a legal contract one person has to
attend the age of 18.
So the correct answer is minor.
Next, which of the following statement
is true?
Correct answer is A. Insurance is a
method of sharing the losses of of few
by many. We have already learned about
this that the insurance is a mechanism
where the losses of few is shared by
many.
Now next one is out of 400 houses each
valued at rs 20,000 on an average four
houses get burned every year resulting
in a combined loss of rs 80,000. What
should be the annual contribution of
each house owner to make good this loss?
This question is also related to the
previous one.
Uh here
total four houses were burned and
because of that total loss is rups
80,000 and this loss is shared by all
these 400 house owners. So when we
divide 80,000 by 400
the answer is rups 200.
Next question is a customer having
complaint regarding his insurance policy
can approach IRDA through.
Friends all of you know
IRDA
set up a online portal to hear the
complaints of any policy holder
and that online portal is known as IGMS.
So the correct answer is a IGMS.
Next is expand the term IGMS. The full
form of IGMS is integrated gans
management system.
The correct answer is C.
Next question is as per the consumer
protection act 1986 who cannot be
classified as a consumer?
Consumer means end user. When we see the
all these four options of answer, the
correct one is B. A person who buys
goods for resell purpose. That means
that person is buying good because he
want to resell.
So the correct answer is B.
Next is the consumer forum is governed
by which act? The correct answer is
consumer protection act 1986.
Next question. Dash has jurisdiction to
entertain matters where value of good or
services and the compensation
claim is up to rupees 20 lakhs. The
correct answer is district forum.
Next, which of the below consumer
grievance redressial agencies would
handle consumer disputes amounting
between rupees 20 lakh and rupees 100
lakh?
Correct answer is state commission.
Next is which of the below statement is
correct with regards to the territorial
jurisdiction of the insurance
ombbertsman.
All of you know that every umbsman have
a a specified area and they have to
operate within that area. So the correct
answer is D. Insurance ombbudzman
operate only within the specified
territorial limits.
Next is how is the complaint to be
launched with the insurance ombbudsman?
The correct answer is the complaint is
to be made in writing.
What is the time limit for approaching
an insurance ambudsman? Friends, we have
already learned about this. To complain
with insurance ambudsman, we have to
reach within a year.
So the correct answer is C within one
year of rejection of the complaint by
the answerer.
Next is which among the following is not
a prerequisite for launching a complaint
with the umbersman. Here question is
asking that not a prerequisite.
So the correct answer is C. Complaint
has to approach a consumer forum prior
to the ambbursman. There is no need. We
can go prior toman with some other forum
or with some court. So the correct
answer is C.
Are there any fee or charges that need
to be paid for lodging the complaint
with the umbersman? Friends, there is no
fee or charges required to complain with
umbersman. So the correct answer is B.
No fee or charges need to be paid.
Next is can a complaint be launched
against a private insurer? Of course, we
can complain against any insurance
company. So the correct answer is B.
Yes, complaint can be launched against
private insurers.
How many insurance ambudsman offices in
India? Currently there are 17 offices.
So the correct answer is C7.
Next is which of the below will be the
most appropriate option for a customer
to lodge an insurance policy related
complaint.
The correct answer is insurance.
Friends, all of us know to complain a
insuranceman is very easy. Why? There is
no fee. There is a time limit for the
decision and there is a also time limit
for the insurer to take action whatever
the decision given by the umbbertsman.
So it is very easy for a policy holder
to complain with insurance umbbertsman.
Next question is dash act as
intermediary and consultant by mutual
agreement between the insured and the
insurer within the terms of reference.
The correct answer is insurance.
Next is which among the following cannot
form the basis for a valid consumer
complaint. Uh when we see all the four
option the correct answer is B.
shopkeeper not advising the customer on
the best product in a category. Let's
say key uh you are going to buy a shop
and you demand lux but the shopkeeper
not saying that dove shop is better than
lux. So there is no complaint arising
because of this. So the correct answer
is B. shopkeeper not advising the
customer on the best product in a
category.
When is it essential for insurable
interest to be present in case of life
insurance?
We already know that at the time of
buying life insurance, insurable
interest should be there. So the correct
answer is A. At the time of taking out
insurance.
Next is which of the below is not
correct with regards to insurable
interest. We already know that there is
a insurable interest between father and
son, between husband and wife and
between employer and employees. So the
correct answer is
C. There is no insurable interest
between two frame. So answer is C.
Friends taking out insurance on one
another.
Next question is which among the
following option cannot be insured by
Romesh. The correct answer is Romesh
friend.
Next is dash relates to inaccurate
statement which are made without any
fraudulent intention.
The correct answer is misrepresentation.
Who devised the concept of human life
value that is HLV?
Uh we have already know the correct
answer is C. Professor Huvener.
Next is Mr. Rajan earns Rs 1 lak 20,000
a year and spend rups 24,000 on himself.
The net earning his family would loss
where he to die prematurely
would be rupes 96,000 per year. Suppose
the rate of interest is 8% find human
life value that is HLV.
So to find out the human life value what
we need to do interest rate is 8% that
means key age 8 by 100 uh is equal to
08. So if we divide 96,000 by 08 you
will get the answer and the correct
answer is rupees 12 lakh.
Which among the following method is a
traditional method that can help to
determine the insurance need by an
individual?
The answer is human life value that is
HLV.
Next is which among the following is not
an objective of tax planning. Uh if you
see the four option the C is correct
answer because tax evasion is not the
objective of tax planning.
Which of the below mentioned insurance
plans has the least or no amount of
saving element?
All the insurance plan having two
elements saving and risk
whether it is endorment whole life money
back or term. But in term plan there is
no saving elements or there are some
term plan which have few or least saving
element
because there is no maturity in term
insurance. So the correct answer is a
term insurance plan.
Next is how does diversification reduce
risk in financial markets.
Friends, we have already learned about
this. If we want to mitigate the risk,
we need to invest our money in different
different products. So the correct
answer is investing funds across various
asset classes.
Which among the following is a wealth
accumulation product. uh when we see the
all four option of answer definitely you
will identify the correct answer shares
because bank loan term insurance policy
savings bank account all these are not a
wealth accumulation product.
Next is during which stage of life will
an individual appreciate past saving the
most? After the retirement
everybody very appreciate his saving.
Why? Because after the retirement their
earning is stopped and whatever they
have saved prior to retirement is very
important for anyone. So the correct
answer is postretirement.
What is the relation between investment
horizon and return?
The correct answer is B. Greater the
investment horizon, the larger the
return.
This is a simple rule. If we invest for
more time,
our return is very high.
If certain terms and conditions of the
policy need to be modified at the time
of issuance, it is done by setting out
the amendments through dash. The correct
answer is endorsement.
Which among the following is an
intangible product?
Intangible means we can feel that but we
cannot touch them. We cannot see them.
So the answer is
life insurance.
The premium paid for whole life
insurance is dash than the premium paid
for term insurance.
The correct answer is higher.
Next is the dash. The premium paid by
you towards your life insurance. The
dash will be the compensation paid to
the beneficiary in the event of your
death.
Here again the answer is higher.
If the premium is higher then the death
benefit is also higher.
What is the objective behind mortgage
redemption insurance?
Correct answer is provide financial
protection for home loan borrowers.
Next, mortgage redemption insurance MRI
can be categorized under.
Answer is decreasing term life
assurance.
In decreasing term assurance, the
premium paid dash over time.
The correct answer is remain constant.
The summation of decreasing term
assurance plan
is decrease but the premium whatever fix
in the first year that will be constant
for remaining years. So the answer is
remain constant.
Which of the below statement is
incorrect with regards to decreasing
term assurance?
Correct answer is B. Premium amount
decrease with the term of coverage.
This question is just opposite to the
previous question.
If Surice mortgages a property and wants
to make a plan to protect his loan which
will most likely be as per his
requirement.
Friends, we have already learned about
this MRI insurance. We can use this plan
to protect our home loan. So the answer
is mortgage redemption insurance.
Next is the sum issued under kman
insurance policy is generally linked to
which of the followings?
We all know kman insurance policy can be
taken for the loss incurred in business.
So the answer is B. Compensate the loss
incurred in business.
Sures accounts for 20% of the company
sales. He is unable to continue his
work. Which policy will help the company
to recover the losses after his
disability?
Friends, we all know that Kimman
insurance
is used for this purpose. So the answer
is D. Kman insurance.
Which of the following are the insurance
money usually associated with the keyman
insurance policy?
The correct answer is B. Profitability
of business.
Next is who among the following is best
advice to purchase a term plan.
Correct answer is an individual who
needs insurance but has a low budget.
Friends, we all know term plan is the
cheapest insurance plan that is
available. So the correct answer is C.
Where was the universal life insurance
introduced first?
Universal life insurance policy
introduced in USA. The correct answer is
A. USA.
Next is which of the below option is
true with regards to MWP act cases?
Statement one, maturity claims checks
are paid to policyh holders. Statement
two, maturity claims checks are paid to
trustees. Friends, we have already
learned about this that under MWP all
the benefits whether it is maturity or
death claim both are paid to trustee. So
the correct answer is B2 is true.
Next is a policy is effected under MWP
act. If the policyh holder does not
appoint a special trustee to receive and
administrator the benefits under the
policy, the sum secured under the policy
become payable to the if we not form
trustee then in case of that the
maturity or death claim both are paid to
official trustee of the estate.
Mahesh ran a business on borrowed
capital. After his sudden demise, all
the creditors are doing their best to go
after Mahes assets. Which of the below
assets is beyond the reach of the
creditors?
Correct answer is C. Term life insurance
policy purchased under section six of
MWP act.
Next, which of the below option is true
with regards to MWP act cases? Statement
one, maturity claims checks are paid to
policy holders. Statement two, maturity
claims checks are paid to trustee. Here
again all the benefits whether it is
maturity or death claim both are paid to
trustee. So the answer is B. 2 is true.
What does a policy lapse means? Policy
lapse means the policy holder
discontinue the payment of premium. So
the answer is policyholder discontinue
premium payment for a policy.
Next is who beers the investment risk in
case of ulips?
Answer is insured. All the risk in ULIP
plan is beer by only policy holders not
by answerer.
Which of the below is an example of a
standard age proof? If we see the answer
options, rasen card, horoscope, village
punch certificate, all these three are
non-estandard. So the correct answer is
C. Passport.
Next is from the below given age proof
documents identify the one which is
classified as non-standard by insurance
company.
If we see the option school certificate
this one is a standard identity card in
case of defense personnel this is also a
standard rasan card this one is
non-standard certificate of baptism this
one is a standard so the correct answer
is C rasan card
which of the below is not a valid
address proof if we see the answer
options
Motor ID card, bank passbook, driving
license. In all these three
there is a address given. But in pen
card only name, father's name and date
of birth is given. So answer is a pen
card. Pen card is not a valid address
proof.
Next is which of the below can be
attributed to moral hazard?
Correct answer is increase risky
behavior following the purchase of
insurance.
The application document used for making
the proposal is commonly known as the
dash. Correct answer is B. Proposal
form.
Next is which of the following documents
is an evidence of the contract between
ensurer and NCO.
Correct answer is policy document.
Policy document is the only evidence
that will prove that the contract done
between insurer and ensured.
What does a first premium received
signify? Choose the most appropriate
option.
When we see the options of answer,
B is the correct answer. First, premium
receipt is the evidence that the policy
contract has begun.
Next, money laundering is the process of
bringing Dash money into an economy by
hiding its Dash origin so that it
appears to be legally acquired.
The answer is a illegal illegal.
In case the policy holder is not
satisfied with the policy, he or she can
return the policy within the free look
period that is within dash of the
receiving of the policy document.
Correct answer is D. 15 days.
Next is which of the below statement is
correct with regards to a policy
returned by a policy holder during the
free look period. Correct answer is C.
The insurance company will refund the
premium after adjusting for
proportionate risk premium for the
period on cover medical examination
expenses and stamp duty charges.
Next question. If the complex language
is used toward a certain policy document
and it has given rise to ambiguity, how
will it generally be construed?
Correct answer is in favor of insured.
Next is which of the below forms the
first part of a standard insurance
policy documents?
Correct answer is a policy schedule.
Next question is for an insurance policy
nomination is allowed under dash of the
insurance act 1938.
Correct answer is C. Section 39.
Next question. Under what circumstances
would the policyh holder need to appoint
an appointee?
If the nominee is minor, then a
policyholder need to appoint an
appointee.
Next question. Which of the below
statement is false with regards to the
nomination?
Correct answer is D. A nominee has full
rights on the whole of the claim.
Next. In order for the policy to acquire
a guaranteed surrender value, for how
long must be the premium paid as per
law?
Correct answer is B. Premium should be
paid for at least three consecutive
years.
Next question is when is a policy deemed
to be lapsed.
Correct answer is C if the premium has
not been paid even during days of grace.
Next, what will happen if the policy
holder does not pay the premium by the
due date and the dies during the grace
period?
Correct answer is C. The insurer will
pay the claim after deducting the unpaid
premium.
Pravin died in a car accident. The
beneficiary submit documents for death
claim. Which of the below document is an
additional document required to be
submitted in case of accidental death as
compared to natural death? In case of
accidental death one more document
required that is inquest report.
Next question is which of the below
death claim will be treated as an early
death claim. If we see all the four
option
A is the correct answer. Why? Because if
the insured dies within 3 years of the
policy duration as we know that any
death claim that occurs within 3 years
we can call them early death claim.
In option B, C and D occur after 3
years. So the correct answer is A.
Next, based on classification of claims,
early or non-early, pick the odd one
out. When we see the options, you may
clearly identify that answer is D.
Pravin dies after 5 and 1/2 years of
buying a term assurance plan. In the
option A, B and C, the death claim
occurs within 3 years. So the correct
answer is D.
Next is given below is a list of
documents to be submitted for a normal
death claim by all beneficiaries in the
event of death of life insured. Pick the
odd one out which is additionally
required to be submitted only in case of
death by accident. Again answer is a
inquisit report. This is the only report
required only in case of accidental
death.
Causes of disease according to
hypocritus.
Answer is all the above.
When was CGHS started?
CGHS means central government health
scheme. It was started in the year 1954.
Identify which of the below statement is
correct.
Answer is A. Health insurance deals with
morbidity. Morbidity means illness.
Health insurance normally used for
illness purpose.
Next is identify the correct full form
of PPN with regards to hospitals in
health insurance.
Full form of PPN is preferred provider
network. Actually PPN is what? It is a
network of hospital authorized by
insurance company for cashless facility.
During investigation of a health
insurance claim presented by Razib Matu,
insurance company finds that instead of
Razib Matu, his brother Rajes Matu had
been admitted to hospital for treatment.
The policy of Raz Matu is not a family
floater plan. This is an example of dash
fraud.
Answer is impersonation.
Next is which of the following codes
captures the procedures performed to
treat the illness.
Answer is C. CPT.
As per IRDA rules, the life insurance
policy claim under investigation will be
paid within
correct answer is 6 month or 180 days.
Next question. Under state insurance
scheme, what percentage of an employee
contributes his salary? Correct answer
is C. 1.75%.
Find out the approximate cause for the
death of the following scenario. AJ
falls off a horse and break his back. He
lies there in a pool of water and
contracts pneumonia. He is admitted to
the hospital and dies because of
pneumonia.
What is the correct answer? Correct
answer is falling of a horse.
Next is Mr. Podar inspired wiring in his
home to protect against fire. It can be
classified under water risk. Answer
is D. Risk reduction.
Sures has taken a policy for 20 years
under which he attains maturity after 20
years. For which scheme he has applied?
Correct answer is endomment plan.
Next. 32 years of capil wants to take
health cover without long processes
medical waiting period and processing
delays
that means he want a non-medical
underwriting policy though correct
answer is B non-medical underwriting
next is Santos has applied for a term
assurance plan his anticipated mortality
ity is significantly lower than a
standard lives and hence could be
charged a lower premium. Under risk
classification, Santos will be
classified under dash. Correct answer is
preferred risk.
Next, Mahes has bought a life insurance
policy with a critical illness rider. He
has made absolute assignment of the
policy in favor of karan. Mahes suffers
a heart attack and there is a claim of
rups 50,000 under the critical illness
rider. To whom will be the payment is
made in this case. The correct answer is
current. If we assign our policy to
someone then the benefit of this policy
will be in the favor of assenee. So the
answer is current.
Sheal is a 32-year-old software engineer
with an expected death rate much lower
than the standard life. Under whom would
sith be classified?
The correct answer is B. Preferred risk.
Next is Vikram has applied for an
insurance policy. His anticipated death
rate is higher than normal. The risk
categorized under dash.
Correct answer is C. Substandard life.
We need to see some abbreviation also.
IRDI,
Insurance Regulatory Development
Authority of India, TPA, Third Party
Administrator, PPN, Preferred Provider
Network, RTI, Right to Information, MRI,
Mortgage Redemption Insurance, MWPA,
Married Woman Property Act, ESIC,
Employee State Insurance Corporation.
We also need to remember some question
which are based on number of days like
decision on proposal form 15 days,
demand of additional documents 10 days,
free look period 15 days to complete the
decision of insurance onwardsman 15
days. Grace period for paying renewal
premium 30 days. Death claim payment 30
days. Prehospization
30 days. Post hospitalization 60 days.
Decision of insurance
90 days. Early death claim death claim
within 3 years. Investigation period for
early death claim 180 days or 6 months.
Rate of interest for delay in death
claim payment. bank rate plus 2%.
Okay friends, thanks for watching my
video. Hope this video will help you a
lot to pass the exam. Especially for
those who want to give their exam in
English language. Uh I tried to cover
all the probable important questions in
this video. I ensure you that after
watching this video, you are able to
give minimum 15 to 20 answers. I have
given some tips in one of my video which
also help you to crack the exam in one
sort. Finally, if you like this video,
then please, please, please subscribe my